Guide to the Human Rights Watch records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series 4: Jeannine Guthrie, Sri Lanka Files1985-1997
  - Embassies of Sri Lanka
  - Belgium--Sri Lanka Puwath, 1996-1997 (Box 480, Folder 7)
  - "Repatriation of Refugees from India to Sri Lanka (13 August to 17 September 1993)", 1993 (Box 480, Folder 8)
  - European Union--Statement, 1995 May 29 (Box 480, Folder 9)
  - General, 1991-1996, (12 folders) (Box 480, Folder 10-21)
  - Human Rights Task Force, 1995 (Box 480, Folder 22)
  - Jahn, Rev. Paul F.--Trip Report, 1993 May (Box 480, Folder 23)
  - Labor, 1991 (Box 480, Folder 24)
  - LTTE--Attacks. 1993 (Box 480, Folder 25)
  - Military Offensives, 1990-1993 (Box 480, Folder 26)
  - Ministry of Foreign Affairs--Sri Lanka: Situation Report, 1995 July (Box 480, Folder 27)
  - Missions/Visits. 1990-1993, (6 folders) (Box 481, Folder 1-6)
  - News Clips, 1993 January -1993 September (12 folders) (Box 481, Folder 7-18)
  - News Clips, 1993 October -1994 September (12 folders) (Box 482, Folder 1-12)
  - NGO Forum on Sri Lanka--Annual Consultation, 1995 November (2 folders) (Box 482, Folder 13-14)
  - Peace Brigades International (PBI) Bulletins, 1993-1995, (2 folders) (Box 482, Folder 15-16)
  - Posters, undated (Box 482, Folder 17)
  - Question and Answer Series, 1996 August (Box 482, Folder 18)
  - Refugees (Box 483)
  - General, 1992-1994, (3 folders) (Box 480, Folder 1-3)
  - Poems, undated (Box 483, Folder 4)
  - "Random News", 1993-1995 (Box 483, Folder 5)
  - South Asia Bulletin, 1992 (Box 483, Folder 6)
  - Sri Lanka Report, undated (Box 483, Folder 7)
  - Tamil Center for Human Rights--Affidavits--Military Killings, 1990-1993, (10 folders) (Box 483, Folder 8-17)
  - Tamil Information Center, 1985 September (Box 483, Folder 18)
  - Trade and Aid, 1993 (Box 483, Folder 19)
  - United Nations
  - General, 1994-1995 (Box 483, Folder 20)
  - Malcolm Rodgers, "Refugees and International Aid Sri Lanka: A Case Study", 1992 May (Box 483, Folder 21)
  - Sri Lankan Government Statement to the UN, 1991 (Box 483, Folder 22)
  - United States--Congressional Advocacy, 1994-1995 (Box 483, Folder 23)
  - Women, 1992-1993 (Box 483, Folder 24)
  - "The World Bank and Poverty Reduction in Sri Lanka: reflections on the Bank's Poverty Assessment", 1995 (Box 483, Folder 25)
  - World Report Updates, 1989-1993, (3 folders) (Box 483, Folder 26-28)
- Series 5: Fraser Wood, China Files, 1989-1992
  Fraser Wood worked as a research associate for Human Rights Watch/Asia from 1989 to 1992. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. The files contain materials associated with groups affected by the aftermath of the Tiananmen Square Massacre such as journalists, political prisoners, and students.
  - Amnesty International (AI)--China Reports, 1989 (Box 484, Folder 1)
  - Asia Watch (AW)--Updates on Arrests, 1989 July -November (Box 484, Folder 2)
  - Catholic Church Target of Renewed Harassment, 1990 May 21 (Box 484, Folder 3)
  - Chron. File--Fraser Wood, 1989-1992 (Box 484, Folder 4)
  - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1989 September (Box 484, Folder 5)
  - Democratic Movement--Names, undated (Box 484, Folder 6)
  - Demonstration Law and Regulation on Social Organizations, 1989 November 1 (Box 484, Folder 7)
  - General, 1989, (13 folders) (Box 484, Folder 8-20)
  - Human Rights in China, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 484, Folder 21-22)
  - List of the "21 Most Wanted" Students, 1989 June 19 (Box 484, Folder 23)
  - Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) Report, 1989-1990 (Box 484, Folder 24)
  - "Political Prisoners in China: One Woman's Story", undated (Box 484, Folder 25)
  - Profiles of Prisoners, undated (Box 484, Folder 26)
  - Wilson, Jeanne L., "Update on Worker Rights in China", 1990 (Box 484, Folder 27)
- Series 6: Mickey Spiegel, China Files, 1985-1991
  Mickey Spiegel has been with Human Rights Watch since 1990 with responsibilities for work on China and Tibet. Among the reports she has authored and coauthored are a series on religious freedom in the People's Republic of China, a directory of political prisoners, and profiles of Tibetans in exile. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Asia Watch (AW) (Box 485)
  - Press Releases, 1985 1989-1990 (Box 485, Folder 1)
  - Work, 1988-1991, (11 folders) (Box 485, Folder 2-12)
  - American Postal Workers Convention, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 13)
  - Anniversary of 1989 Democracy Movement, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 14)
  - Arrests--Updates, 1989-1990, (2 folders) (Box 485, Folder 15-16)
  - Asian Games, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 17)
  - Associated Press (AP), 1989 June 4 (Box 485, Folder 18)
  - Asylum
  - Apply for Funding--People, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 19)
  - Bai Mong, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 20)
  - Bei Ling, 1989-1991 (Box 485, Folder 21)
  - Cases, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 485, Folder 22-23)
  - Chen Ziming, 1989 December (Box 485, Folder 24)
  - Feng YuChuan, 1989-1990 (Box 485, Folder 25)
  - Fu li (Su Xiaokang's wife), 1990 (Box 485, Folder 26)
  - Hao Jun, 1989 (Box 485, Folder 27)
  - Later Placements, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 28)
  - Law Office of Claudia Slovinksy, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 29)
  - Lee Ming, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 30)
  - Ma Jinyuan, 1989 (Box 485, Folder 31)
  - Meng Sheng, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 32)
  - Peng Zhaoping, 1990 [restricted until 2066] (Box 485, Folder 33)
  - Ren, MeiYue, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 34)
  - Tao, Dr. Xiao Cheng, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 35)
  - Tao, Xiaochun and Zhang Hua Zhong, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 36)
  - Wu, Haicheng, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 37)
  - Xu Gang, undated (Box 485, Folder 38)
  - Yang, King Guo, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 39)
  - Yu Desheng, 1989-1990 (Box 485, Folder 40)
  - Zhu Zhiying, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 41)
  - Zu Man San, 1990 (Box 485, Folder 42)
  - Zoya Wei, 1989 (Box 485, Folder 43)
  - Beijing Spring--Documentary--Draft, 1990 February(4 folders) (Box 486, Folder 1-4)
  - Campaign against crime, 1991 (Box 486, Folder 5)
  - China Symposium--Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 486, Folder 6)
  - Chinese Boat People/Refugees, 1990-1991 (Box 486, Folder 7)
  - Chron. Files, 1989-1990, (4 folders) (Box 486, Folder 8-11)
  - Correspondence
  - General, 1989-1991, (7 folders) (Box 486, Folder 12-18)
  - Robin, Munro, 1989-1991, (6 folders) (Box 486, Folder 19-24)
  - Corruption/Purges, 19989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 487, Folder 1-2)
  - Diao Yu Tai event, October 1990 (Box 487, Folder 3)
  - Documentation Centers--Democracy Movement, 1989 (Box 487, Folder 4)
  - Domestic Issues, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 487, Folder 5-6)
  - Foreign Investment, 1989-1991 (Box 487, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Policy, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 487, Folder 8-9)
  - General, 1990, (4 folders) (Box 487, Folder 10-13)
  - Government--General, 1990-1991 (Box 487, Folder 14)
  - Health, 1990-1991 (Box 487, Folder 15)
  - Hijacking, 1990 October (Box 487, Folder 16)
  - Hostage--Dongzhen Hai, 1990 (Box 487, Folder 17)
  - "Human Rights Violations Since (1989 June 3)", 1989 November (Box 487, Folder 18)
  - Ideology, 1990-1991 (Box 487, Folder 19)
  - Labor
  - Forced Labor--General, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 487, Folder 20-21)
  - Labor, 1990-1991 (Box 487, Folder 22)
  - Workers, 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 487, Folder 23-24)
  - Legal System/Texts, 1989 (Box 488, Folder 1)
  - Martial Law, 1990 (Box 488, Folder 2)
  - Missions--Hong Kong Visit, 1991 (Box 488, Folder 3)
  - Nakamura, Kimiyoshi (Publisher), 1990 (Box 488, Folder 4)
  - News Clips
  - Chinese, 1989-1991, (80 folders) (Box 488, Folder 5-84)
  - English, 1988-1991, (35 folders) (Box 489, Folder 1-35)
  - "Parole" Admissions--Refugees, 1987-1989 (Box 490, Folder 1)
  - Police and Military, 1989-1991 (Box 490, Folder 2)
  - Press Chronology, 1989-1991 (Box 490, Folder 3)
  - Prisoner Profiles, 1989 (Box 490, Folder 4)
  - Reforms, 1990 (Box 490, Folder 5)
  - Responses
  - Paal, 1990 February26 (Box 490, Folder 6)
  - Scholars Letter, 1989 (Box 490, Folder 7)
  - Schifter, Richard (U.S. Asst. Sec. of State)--Visit, 1990 December 19 (Box 490, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, plans, etc., 1989-1991 (Box 490, Folder 9)
  - Survey (Wang Ruowang), undated (Box 490, Folder 10)
  - Taiwan (3), 1990 January 5 (Box 490, Folder 11)
  - Tibet, 1988-1990 (Box 490, Folder 12)
  - Torture--Asia Watch (AW) Submission to the UN Committee Against Torture", undated (Box 490, Folder 13)
  - Trade, 1990-1991 (Box 490, Folder 14)
  - United States
  - Department of Justice Immigration and Naturalization Service--Application Work, 1989 (Box 490, Folder 15)
  - Kent Wiedemann--State Dept. Official, 1990 (Box 490, Folder 16)
  - Vause, W. Gary, "Tibet to Tiananmen: Chinese Human Rights and United States Foreign Policy", 1989 (Box 490, Folder 17)
  - Wire Services, 1989-1991, (19 folders) (Box 490, Folder 18-36)